<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Piezo-Shoes</string>
    <string name="app_desc">Please connect your device to a power source.
        The charging status should show as charging.
        Check your battery condition and observe if the charging percentage changes over time.</string>
    <string name="introduction">
        As wearable electronic devices evolve and proliferate, there will be a growing need for more power
delivery to distributed points around the human body. Today, much of that storage is provided by
batteries and power delivery is via wires. The current approach to power distribution is clearly
becoming problematic -- as more appliances are carried, we are forced to either use more small
batteries that require replacement everywhere or run wires through our clothing to supply appliances
from a central power source. Both are undesirable. A better solution is clearly to generate power where
it is being used, bypassing the storage and distribution problem altogether. As power requirements
drop for most wearable devices, it is no longer infeasible to harvest a useful amount of energy
&quot;parasitically&quot; from a normal range of human activity.
    </string>
    <string name="literature">The project is be accomplished by using piezoelectric materials. Piezoelectricity, also called the
piezoelectric effect, is the ability of certain materials to generate an alternating current voltage when
actuated. Certain ceramics, Rochelle salts, and various other solids exhibit this effect. For example,
(Pb[ZrxTi1−x]O3 where,0≤x≤1), also called PZT, will generate measurable electricity when their structure
is deformed by about 0.1% of the original dimension(International AAAI Conference on Social Media and
Weblogs, 2012). In this project, the generated electricity on a specific time will be recorded and
determine if it would be enough to completely charge a Li-ion battery or a high capacity capacitor.
The project is be accomplished by using piezoelectric materials. Piezoelectricity, also called the
piezoelectric effect, is the ability of certain materials to generate an alternating current voltage when
actuated. Certain ceramics, Rochelle salts, and various other solids exhibit this effect. For example,
(Pb[ZrxTi1−x]O3 where,0≤x≤1), also called PZT, will generate measurable electricity when their structure
is deformed by about 0.1% of the original dimension(International AAAI Conference on Social Media and
Weblogs, 2012). In this project, the generated electricity on a specific time will be recorded and
determine if it would be enough to completely charge a Li-ion battery or a high capacity capacitor.
The piezoelectric effect, by which a material generates an electric potential in response to a
temperature change, was studied by Carl Linnaeus and Franz Aepinus in the mid-18th century. Drawing
on this knowledge, both René Just Haüy and Antoine César Becquerel posited a relationship between
mechanical stress and electric charge; however, experiments by both proved inconclusive. The first
demonstration of the direct piezoelectric effect was in 1880 by the brothers Pierre Curie and Jacques
Curie. They combined their knowledge of pyroelectricity with their understanding of the underlying
crystal structures that gave rise to pyroelectricity to predict crystal behaviour, and demonstrated the
effect using crystals of tourmaline, quartz, topaz, cane sugar, and Rochelle salt (sodium potassium
tartrate tetrahydrate). Quartz and Rochelle salt exhibited the most piezoelectricity.</string>
</resources>
